Finding aid to the Kate Mott Greene Stephenson papers CA.MS.00170
Smith College Archives
Kate Mott Greene Stephenson papers
1930-1989
Smith College Archives
Stephenson, Kate Mott Greene
CA.MS.00170
0.625 linear feet (2 containers)
The collection consists of class notebooks from courses taken by Kate Mott Greene Stephenson (Class of 1933) and the correspondence she received from Dorcas Brigham (Class of 1918), an Assistant Professor of Botany (1923-1928).
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
These are the papers of Kate Mott Greene Stephenson (Class of 1933) and donated to the College Archives by her in 2000, and her daughter Helen S. Weary in 2005.
Biographical / Historical
Kate Mott Greene Stephenson (Class of 1933) hailed from Pennsylvania. Upon her graduation from Smith College she held various clerical positions until her marriage to William B. Stephenson. William Stephenson was a mechanical engineer (Penn State, B.S.) and eventually president of Allen Sherman Hoff Company of Pennsylvania. Stephenson often accompanied her husband on his many business trips especially to Europe. She noted that in her lifetime she was mostly housewife, mother and grandmother and was involved with community activities in the various places where they lived. She died on January 20, 2005.
Related Material
Researchers should also view:
42. Dorcas Brigham Papers
80. Class of 1933 Records
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of class notebooks from 1931-1933 related to art history, botany, English literature and modern European history. The modern European history notes (History 34) are most likely from lectures by Walter Carl Barnes. While at Smith College, Stephenson formed a friendship with Dorcas Brigham (Class of 1918), an Assistant Professor of Botany (1923-1928). The papers include the correspondence Stephenson received from Brigham from 1933-1984. There are photographs from her days at Smith College (including house portraits) and some snapshots from class reunions, plus a few personal ones.
Smith College -- Students; Smith College--Alumni and alumnae; Stephenson, Kate Mott Greene; Stephenson, Kate Mott Greene
- Miscellaneous memorabilia, 1931- 1980s (Box 2051, Folder 1)
- Correspondence from Dorcas Brigham, undated (Box 2051, Folder 2)
- Correspondence from Dorcas Brigham, 1933 (Box 2051, Folder 3)
- Correspondence from Dorcas Brigham, 1934 (Jan.-Sep.) (Box 2051, Folder 4)
- Correspondence from Dorcas Brigham, 1934 (Oct.-Dec.) (Box 2051, Folder 5)
- Correspondence from Dorcas Brigham, 1935 (Jan.-Apr.) (Box 2051, Folder 6)
- Correspondence from Dorcas Brigham, 1935 (May-Dec.) (Box 2051, Folder 7)
- Correspondence from Dorcas Brigham, 1936-1939 (Box 2051, Folder 8)
- Correspondence from Dorcas Brigham, 1940-1942 (Box 2051, Folder 9)
- Correspondence from Dorcas Brigham, 1943-1949 (Box 2051, Folder 10)
- Correspondence from Dorcas Brigham, 1950-1969 (Box 2051, Folder 11)
- Correspondence from Dorcas Brigham, 1970-1978 (Box 2051, Folder 12)
- Correspondence from Dorcas Brigham, 1980-1984 (Box 2051, Folder 13)
- Art history notebooks, 1931-1932 (Box 2051, Folder 14)
- Botany notebooks and plant lists, 1930-1932 (Box 2051.1, Folder 15)
- English literature notebook; French papers, 1930-1931 (Box 2051.1, Folder 16)
- History notebooks, 1932-1933 (Box 2051.1, Folder 17)
- Photographs, 1930-1980s (Box 2051.1, Folder 18)